Guide to the James V. Scaife Civil War items, 1861-1915.
Scaife, James V. Civil War items, 1861-1915.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
James V. Scaife Civil War items, 1861-1915, 1911-1915 (bulk).
2030
James V. Scaife, 1868-1930.
.3 cubic ft.
Lithographed covers, correspondence, photographs, scrapbooks, an attendence roster, obituraries, and other printed items.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Civil War items collected by James V. Scaife. Items include lithographed Civil War covers; letters to Scaife concerning Civil War research; photographs of battle fields; scrapbooks of newspaper clippings concerning the Civil War and other events in American history; roster of attendance of the Wilder's Brigade reunion at Chattanooga in 1913; obituaries and other clippings pertaining to Civil War veterans; and other printed items.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Letters, photographs, scrapbooks, and other materials concerning the Civil War and Civil War veterans.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Civil War items collected by James V. Scaife. Items include lithographed Civil War covers; letters to Scaife concerning Civil War research; photographs of battle fields; scrapbooks of newspaper clippings concerning the Civil War and other events in American history; roster of attendance of the Wilder's Brigade reunion at Chattanooga in 1913; obituaries and other clippings pertaining to Civil War veterans; and other printed items.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Scaife, James Verner.
Subjects:
Chattanooga, Battle of, Chattanooga, Tenn., 1863.
Places:
Tennessee--History--Civil War, 1861-1865--Campaigns.; United States--History--Civil War, 1861-1865.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
NOTE: The Scaife Civil War covers were removed from a scrapbook because of its poor condition; following is a copy of the table of contents:
Colored
4
Upham's U.S. sett
8
House That Uncle Sam Built
20
Magee's sett of U.S. en.
24
New York sett
36
Miscellaneous
40
Washington
50
McClellan
65
Scott
75
Lincoln
85
Ellsworth
95
CONTAINER LIST
- Scaife Civil War covers, 304 items, lithographed by:
  - Bloom and Smith, N.Y.C. (3) (Box 1)
  - Edward Cogan, Philadelphia (1) (Box 1)
  - James Gates, Cincinnati (2) (Box 1)
  - Gibson & Co., Cincinnati (1) (Box 1)
  - Harbach & Brother, Phila. (7) (Box 1)
  - J.E. Hayes, Massachusetts (1) (Box 1)
  - F. Hedge, Boston (1) (Box 1)
  - Hoffman & Knickerbocker, Albany (1) (Box 1)
  - Johnson-Dana (1) (Box 1)
  - F.K. Kimmel, N.Y.C. (2) (Box 1)
  - King & Baird, Phila. (2) (Box 1)
  - J. Magee, Phila. (40) (Box 1)
  - Chas. Magnus, N.Y.C. (74) (Box 1)
  - J.C. Mickley, Philadelphia (1) (Box 1)
  - Mumford & Co., Cincinnati (2) (Box 1)
  - N.Y. Union, Broadway, N.Y.C. (1) (Box 1)
  - Reagles & Co., N.Y.C. (35) (Box 1)
  - S.C. Upham, Phila. (40) (Box 1)
  - J.G. Wells, N.Y. C. (2) (Box 1)
  - Whittemore & Co., Boston (3) (Box 1)
  - S.H. Zahm, Lancaster, Pa. (1) (Box 1)
  - 83 by unnamed firms (Box 1)
- Other Scaife Civil War items:
  - 4 letters to Scaife, 1911-1915, cc. of letter from Scaife (Box 1)
  - 10 photographs of battlefield [Gettysburg?] and environs (Box 1)
  - Ca. 248 newspaper and magazine clippings pertaining to the Civil War - many are obituaries of veterans (Box 1)
  - 1 pamphlet - pages from The Collector [rosters of Confederate officers] (Box 1)
  - 1 coin catalogue [Confederate money, etc.] (Box 1)
  - Scrapbook containing:
    - 57 articles pasted in - about Civil War events, Andrew Jackson, the Revolution, John Wilkes Booth, death of President Garfield, burial of Washington (Box 1)
    - 91 loose clippings in back of scrapbook - many about surviving veterans of the Civil War (Box 1)
  - 1 advertising card - Miller's Machine Shop, Chambersburg, Pa. - To TC Coll. (Box 1)
  - 1 train schedule of 1903 - in Russian & French (Box 1)
  - 1 name card - Robert H. Fitzhugh (Box 1)
  - 1 newspaper clipping about Arkansas Hot Springs; also 1 clipping on Niagara Falls (Box 1)
- Non-Civil War items:
  - 1 photo of Negro seaman, 1893 (Box 1)
  - 1 Epiphany Church, [Philadelphia ?] 1895 [blue print-type] (Box 1)
  - 1 Scotch Presbyterian Church [Phila.?] 1895 (Box 1)